MEENAKSHIS

Senior Financial Analyst

An Adaptive and determined professional who has an extensive knowledge of accounts payable & receivables procedures. Team-oriented with strong communication skills and ability to constantly learn and adapt according to the task at hand.

- 9+Years of Total experience with Accounts payable, Receivables and Cash Control.
- 1 Year as Senior Financial Analyst in Vibhu Healthcare Pvt Ltd.
- 2.5 Years as Senior process associate and 1.5 years as Team lead in DHL Global Freight Forwarding.
- 6 Months as Cash control Analyst in Conduent.
- 2 Years as Process associate and 1 year as Senior process Associate in Tata Consultancy Services
- 10 months as Process Associate in R.R.Donnelley.
- Awarded R&R (Rewards & Recognition) by Client twice for maintaining consistent quality and productivity.
- Awarded BPS (Best Star Performer) 8 times for the outstanding performance and skills exhibited in TCS.
- Received Star Performer Award for 8 times in DHL for adhering to Quality and Productivity metrics.

Bachelor of Commerce, Hindu College, Madras University, Chennai

Financial Analyst - Vibhu Healthcare LLP, Chennai

- Worked to maintain accurate and detailed information for patient records.
- Aimed to provide the highest level of customer service by remaining organized, punctual and accurate.
- Preparation of Monthly Reporting which gives the total business and financial information of agencies in periodic basis with respect to total volume of sales, Collection, Aging, Revenue.
- Analyze and file GST based on slabs.
- Handled GSTR-2B by submitting through e invoice.
- Analyze and prepare month-end/year-end financial statements.
- Manage and keep the company's tax database up to date.

Application Used: ShopAid and Marg ERP 9.

Team Lead - DHL Global Freight Forwarding, Chennai

- Adhere to Quality and Productivity metrics.
- Performance ratings and reviews.
- Ensure to monitor all Freight invoices are processed in SAP as per SLA & reviewing of Intercompany monthly billing.
- Conduct regular audits internally using double entries check database macro.
- Building & sustenance of Risk & Control Matrix (RACMs) for all process, ensuring teams are aligned to it.
- Supported ISO and PWC audits (Internal and external) on quarterly basis.
- Proactively identify areas where internal controls and procedures can be improved in the
 preparation of the account reconciliations and propose solutions to mitigate risk and close
 gaps.
- Manage the process for elevating control risks to senior levels when appropriate.
- Lead in the developing and improving management reporting.
- Handling vendor reconciliations and Month end closure activities.
- Preparing MPR and QPR deck for business reviews & preparing adhoc reports up on client request.
- Perform Bank reconciliation activities and Updating KPI matrix.
- Performing Monthly and Quarterly recons in Blackline tool.

OBJECTIVE

SUMMARY

ACHIEVEMENTS

EDUCATION

Jun 2008 - May 2011

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2023 - Present

Aug 2018 - Jun 2023

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

May 2013 - Oct 2016

Application Used:

LOGIS AIR AND OCEAN FREIGHT, CW1, JBA, WORKSPACE 3.2, ISC.

Cash Control Analyst - Conduent, Bangalore

- Booking of Wire payments.
- · Wire Payments Forecasting.
- · Wire Payment processing- Regular Wires/ SAP Wires.
- · Payment confirmation for the wire transactions completed.
- · Self audit for the Wire transactions.
- · Handling ACH Pre Funding & Queries.
- · Returned cheques handling.
- · Stop payments handling.
- JE accruals for outstanding wire payments.

Application Used:

• GEPARA,ODM 1 2 & 3, JPMC, DACOR

Senior Process Associate - Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai

- Processed accounts payable cheques, wire transfers and ACH payments.
- · Processed employee expense reports and one card maintenance.
- Maintained vendor master files and handled monthly client calls.
- Reviewed vendor statements and purchase orders, investigated and resolved open issues.
- Assisting month closure activities regarding A/P, A/R including bank reconciliation and sub ledger books.
- Played Vital role in adhering to compliance requirements and achieved good scores in Internal and External Audits.
- Sending chase emails and reminder letters to customers and track the payment received.
- Processing credit request. Worked on credit management to monitor the credit exposure of customers and requesting additional security if required.
- Estimating and forecasting the cash collections volume on monthly basis using a tool
- Preparation of balance sheet reconciliation and clearing open line items.
- Preparing and reviewing files for parked invoice report, AR overdue invoices and follow up.
- Responsible for sending the Debtor Activity & Aging Reports on a weekly Basis
 to the clients which will enable to the clients to collect the invoices on due
 dates.
- Standard Operating Procedure Preparation of SOP for each activity in the process, which serves as an operational guide to the users, provides an idea about the scope of work and responsibilities.

Application Used:

SAP, GP TOOL, AS400, WELLS FARGO AND OMS

Process Associate - R.R. Donnelley, Chennai

- · Keying PO invoices.
- Quality checking of Invoices which has been parked before posting.
- Exception processing of invoices.
- Handling vendor payment queries through email.

Application Used:

SAP

Jul 2012 - Apr 2013